OBIORA UKWUANI

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

OBJECTIVE

Front-End Developer with good experience in designing and developing user friendly interfaces, testing and debugging, and good in team work and ready to contribute in the achievement of company goals. Proven ability in optimizing web functionalities that improve data retrieval and workflow efficiencies.

EXPERIENCE

2022 - Present | United States of Africa(USAF)

Front-end Developer | Volunteer

- Develop a USAF front-end website
- Working in a team.
- Gave feedback at each point in the website development, and debugging was done regularly.

2022 – 2023 | Africa Mental Health Reform Consortium(AMHEC)

Web Developer / WordPress

- Built from scratch a website, showing the caring movement being undertaken by AMHEC in ensuring mental health in Africa.
- Worked in a team.
- Gave feedback at each point in the website development, and debugging was done regularly.

2016 – Present | Dave Computers and KC Gaming Agents' Outlet Damaturu

Networking and Software Installations Manager

- Checks and ensures that all network connections; ports, hubs and USB
 are functioning properly; and also ensures that wireless network
 connections are all transmitting well.
- Oversees that all online and offline file sharing between computers are accessible and functioning as it should.

CONTACT

- 08131907599
- <u>obioraukwuani@gmail.com</u>
- easyappx.github.io/portfolio/
- Map-Global Abuja FCT

SKILLS

- HTML / CSS / JavaScript
- JavaScript / JQuery
- JavaScript / React
- JSON
- PHP / MySQL
- WordPress / Bootstrap
- Git / GitHUB
- MS Word / MS Excel
- MS PowerPoint

COMPETENCIES

- Web Development Projects
- Website Design Using HTML & CSS
- Web Page Programming

 / Programming
- Responsive Web Design
- Team collaboration

- Applies useful standards, policies and regulatory guidelines to promote and provide a conducive working environment.
- Devotes special emphasis to punctuality and works to maintain outstanding attendance record.

2021 – 2022 | Web Development Projects for Students' (Students' Final Defence Programs)

Web Developer

- Uses critical thinking to break down problems, evaluate possible solutions and make decisions.
- Built responsive web based platforms / systems for students from scratch for their final defence program.
- Learn new skills and apply them to daily tasks of web development to improve efficiency and productivity.

2021 – 2021 | Ebonyi State University; Nacos Website Design and Development

NACOS (National Association of Computing Students) Web

Development Associate (Ebonyi State University Chapter)

- Resolved problems, improved operations and provided exceptional service.
- Improved design operations through consistent hard work and dedication.
- Contributed to development of a standard website for 2017/2018 Nacos chapter for computer science students.
- Completed paperwork, recognizing discrepancies and addressing for resolution.

2020 – 2021 | Goziconarc Buildings Abakaliki (Private Enterprise)

Web Developer

- Planned website development from scratch; designed and sketched samples of the website
- Designed and developed user-friendly and responsive website that allows users to explore through a series of building adverts for clients.
- Fixed bugs from existing websites and implemented enhancements that significantly improved web functionality and speed
- Coded website using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP languages

- Search Engine Optimization
- Troubleshooting / Debugging

LANGUAGES

- English
- Hausa
- Igbo

EDUCATION

2017 – 2022 | Ebonyi State University Abakaliki – Abakaliki Ebonyi State

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

2004 – 2010 | Sacred Heart Seminary – Nsude Enugu State

Senior School Certificate Examination: SSCE

2010 – 2011 | Pope John Paul II Major Seminary – Akwa Anambra State

Latin Diploma: Latin

CERTIFICATIONS | COURSES | TRAINING

2022 - 2022 | Udemy: Instructors; Codestars Rob Percival & Nick Walter

Complete Android Oreo Developer Course, Java – Build 23 Apps

2022 – 2022 | Inspired Ace: Public Speaking & Business Development Skills

Public Speaking \$ Business Development Skills

2021 - 2022 | Udemy: Instructors; George Levy

Cryptocurrency Fundamentals: Buy, Sell, Trade Cryptocurrency

2017 | Skill Acquisition, General Entrepreneurial and Career Development

Career Link And Skill Acquisition Company (CLASAC)

2015 | Green-White Technologies LTd.

Business Ideas and Entrepreneurship Skills

2014 – 2015 | Pax Herbal Clinic Laboratory – Ohum Monastery Benin State

Pax Practitioner / Agent

2013 | DELES Programme Nigeria: Development Education and Leadership

Services

DELES Leadership & Human Development

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

• Developed a responsive website promoting mental health in Africa; Africa Mental Health Reform Consortium (AMHEC).

- Collaborated with a team of nine developers in the development of a website for NACOS, Ebonyi State University Chapter; Computer Science Department.
- Used Microsoft Excel to develop an inventory tracking spreadsheets, which was later imported to a Record Keeping System built with HTML CSS and PHP for a client.

REFEREES:

Available on request.